<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Xabier Amado</title><link>http://www.example.com/</link><description>Recent content on Xabier Amado</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 01:13:43 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gameboy Color emulator</title><link>http://www.example.com/projects/rust-gameboy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 22:58:33 -0300</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/projects/rust-gameboy/</guid><description>I wrote this emulator while learning about Rust. The emulator is complete, although some games that rely on specific quirks on the original hardware might not work perfectly.
For the most part it was able to play through any of the &amp;ldquo;popular&amp;rdquo; games including the amazing audio track in Zelda&amp;rsquo;s splash screen.
Zelda Link&amp;#39;s Awakening for GameBoy Color. Ignore de 44ms in the title, Windows snip tool freezes the rendering while taking the screenshot.</description></item><item><title>Spark Game Engine</title><link>http://www.example.com/projects/spark/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 22:58:33 -0300</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/projects/spark/</guid><description>Spark is a Game Engine I have been working on for&amp;hellip; ever. Started originally in 2009, but since it was always a pet/educational project I never really did anything with it, other than, well, learn! I don&amp;rsquo;t have any delusions of ever it becoming anything other than a way for me to learn and research things that interest me.
Key features:
Some C++ 20 features. I&amp;rsquo;m not keen on using modern C++ just because it exists, but there&amp;rsquo;s a few things that I do like, like lambdas, std::function, auto for iterators and most recently std::format, which is much more clean than any string formatting ever before in C++.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://www.example.com/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 22:21:35 -0300</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/about/</guid><description>My name is Xavier Amado and I&amp;rsquo;m a Game Developer!
Skills Game Development C++, C#, Lua 3D Math Optimization and Performance Multiplatform (Nintendo DS, Nintendo Wii, Xbox 360, Windows, Linux, OSX) Graphics and Rendering (OpenGL, Wii&amp;rsquo;s GFX API, DirectX) Torque, Unity, Unreal Web Development PHP, MySQL, CSS, JS, Vuejs node.js, mongodb, redis Other Some Experience: Python, Lua, Rust, Assembly Linux server maintenance Credited Games XDefiant - Ubisoft Rocksmith+ - Ubisoft FarCry 6 - Ubisoft FIFA 2019 Switch - EA Atmosphir - Minor Studios (Windows, OSX and iPad) Lucha Libre AAA: Héroes del Ring - Sabarasa (Wii / PSP) Atrévete a Soñar - Sabarasa (Wii) Save the Turtles - Sabarasa (DSi, iOS) Alt-Play: Jason’s Rohrer - Sabarasa (DSi) Primrose - Sabarasa (DSi) Art of Ink - Sabarasa (DSi) Protocol - Sabarasa (Wii) Horizon - Sabarasa (Wii) Protothea - Sabarasa (Wii) Marble Blast XP - Indie (NetJet) RacerXtreme - Indie (PC) Camelot Galway Indie (PC) Experience Technical Director - Globant Mar 2016 - Present As Technical Director at Globant&amp;rsquo;s Gaming Studio I lead the studio&amp;rsquo;s game development practice, follow new business opportunities, empower our teams and developers to grow and just in general help the studio move forward.</description></item></channel></rss>