<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Xabier Amado</title><link>http://xamado.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Xabier Amado</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 01:13:43 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://xamado.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gameboy Color emulator</title><link>http://xamado.github.io/projects/rust-gameboy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 22:58:33 -0300</pubDate><guid>http://xamado.github.io/projects/rust-gameboy/</guid><description>I wrote this emulator while learning about Rust. The emulator is complete, although some games that rely on specific quirks on the original hardware might not work perfectly.
For the most part it was able to play through any of the &amp;ldquo;popular&amp;rdquo; games including the amazing audio track in Zelda&amp;rsquo;s splash screen.
Zelda Link&amp;#39;s Awakening for GameBoy Color. Ignore de 44ms in the title, Windows snip tool freezes the rendering while taking the screenshot.</description></item><item><title>Rust Pathtracer</title><link>http://xamado.github.io/projects/rust-pathtracer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 22:58:33 -0300</pubDate><guid>http://xamado.github.io/projects/rust-pathtracer/</guid><description>Another small project to have a bit more fun with Rust. It&amp;rsquo;s a very basic Path tracer.
Basic path tracer</description></item><item><title>Spark Game Engine</title><link>http://xamado.github.io/projects/spark/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 22:58:33 -0300</pubDate><guid>http://xamado.github.io/projects/spark/</guid><description>Spark is a Game Engine I have been working on for&amp;hellip; ever. Started originally in 2009, but since it was always a pet/educational project I never really did anything with it, other than, well, learn! I don&amp;rsquo;t have any delusions of ever it becoming anything other than a way for me to learn and research things that interest me.
Key features:
Some C++ 20 features. I&amp;rsquo;m not keen on using modern C++ just because it exists, but there&amp;rsquo;s a few things that I do like, like lambdas, std::function, auto for iterators and most recently std::format, which is much more clean than any string formatting ever before in C++.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://xamado.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 22:21:35 -0300</pubDate><guid>http://xamado.github.io/about/</guid><description>My name is Xavier Amado and I&amp;rsquo;m a Game Developer!
I consider myself a problem-solver, hardworking and curious individual, most of my experience comes from a personal itch about learning how things work.
I started &amp;ldquo;programming&amp;rdquo; when I was only 6 years old on a Commodore64 using Logo, then moved on to Basic, Pascal, C++ and never stopped. My first involvement in real game development was when GarageGames open-sourced the Torque Game Engine, back in a world where Game Engines were close guarded secrets and licenses costed millions, it was a great learning opportunity for me.</description></item><item><title>UE5: Accessing BP components from CDO</title><link>http://xamado.github.io/posts/test/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://xamado.github.io/posts/test/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was recently trying to create an actor during runtime, and populate it with the components from another actor, specified as the &amp;ldquo;template&amp;rdquo; through it&amp;rsquo;s class. This other actor wasn&amp;rsquo;t being Spawned, but rather used as a reference.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>